

Ramsay Shiells

Software Developer

Inverurie, Scotland

Profile

Software Developer with 5+ years of experience. Passionate about learning and exploring new technologies and I believe in producing clear and concise code in well structured applications.

I also like cooking, gaming, playing the guitar, skiing and running.

Experience

Software Developer - Evolve Ltd

March 2014 - Present

- Designing, implementing and testing features in existing and new applications
- Maintaining and fixing bugs in historical applications
- Producing documentation
- Creating releases
- o Supporting and mentoring Graduate Software Developers

Graduate Software Developer - Evolve Ltd September 2012 - March 2014

- o Designing, implementing and testing features in existing applications
- Maintaining and fixing bugs in historical applications
- Customer Support and Operational Support

Ski Instructor & Attendant - Alford Ski Centre August 2004 - May 2015

- Instructing children and adults from beginner to expert level
- o Maintenance of the dry ski slope and equipment
- Taking bookings and payments

Education

MSc Cloud Computing - Aberdeen Univeristy September 2011 - September 2012

"Creating, Publishing and Visualising Data for the Semantic Web" MSc Project in collaboration with IBM

BSc Hons Computing Science - Aberdeen Univeristy September 2008 - September 2011

"Making Linked Data Accessible"

Honours Project in collaboration with Aberdeen City Council

Projects

Android App - Grampian Transport Museum January 2017 - March 2017

Application used to supplement exhibits with images and videos

Details

± 13-02-1988

www.ramsayshiells.info

ramsayshiells@me.com

Programming Languages

🖺 Java

Js Javascript

日 HTML

■ SQL

፱ CSS

■ RDF

PHP

Frameworks

Alfresco

Spring

dojo Dojo

JQuery

Android SDK

✓ .NET

Tools

Eclipse

V Maven

Microsoft SQL Server

M TFS

★ Atom

MySQL

Github

🚏 aws